ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/102 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Justice Photographs
1900-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/102 P
12 cubic feet
12 linear ft.
Photographs, publications (documents).
This collection contains photographs used in, or considered for use in, Justice. Photographs document a wide range of ILGWU activities and institutions, as well as many ILGWU members, staff, and officers.
7128357
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 16, 2010
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 20, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Justice was the official organ of the ILGWU from 1919 to 1995.
Scope and Contents
Justice was the official weekly publication of the ILGWU from 1919 to 1995. The union employed photographers to record events and activities for use in the publication. This collection contains photographs used in, or considered for use in, Justice. The photographs document a wide range of ILGWU activities and institutions, as well as many ILGWU members, staff, and officers. They are arranged by subject, such as an individual, Local number, Region or Department name, event (convention, parade) or topic (shop scenes, imports).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780/051 mf: ILGWU Justice on Microfilm 5780/051 PUBS: ILGWU Publications Justice 5780/180: ILGWU Publication "Justice" Index
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States
7128357
- Agreements and Negotiations: Outerwear Negotiations, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes: Chaikin at Dress talks meeting, New York Hilton Hotel, 1/28/76; Chaikin at Dress Joint Council, New York Hilton Hotel, 1/29/76; New York Dress Joint Council approves contract settlement with VP David Gingold, secretary-treasurer Sam Byer, VP Murray Gross, and President Chaikin, NY Hilton, 2/5/76; Chaikin speaking at opening of contract negotiations, Sheraton Centre, 3/21/79; ILGWU General Executive Board with Pres. Chaikin discussing current outerwear negotiations, 3/20/79; Pres. Chaikin with ILGWU Sec'y-Treas. Shelley Appleton and Executive VP Wilbur Daniels at press conference, Apr. 1979; Two pages of "Justice" with picture of Local 91, children's wear; Local 155, Knitgoods, rainwear workers, and Cloakmakers, May 1979; Cloakmakers, May 1979; Local 155, Knitgoods, May 1979; Local 91 Children's wear, May 1979; Chaikin at press conference with reporters, May 30, 1979
- Agreements and Negotiations (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Includes: Chaikin at Eastern Penna Region ILGWU, no date; contract negotiations 1982, 6/3/82; Chaikin speaking to members of Westchester- Rockland District, White Plains, NY 3/8/82; Chaikin at meeting; Asian women voting, Local 23-25, 6/3/82
- Agreements and Negotiations (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Includes: Pres. Chaikin and General Sec'y-Treas. Jay Mazur listen to members' concerns, March 1985; Union negotiators with employers at sportswear negotiations, 3/31/82; workers ratify agreement, Los Angeles, 9/1/81
- Agreements and Negotiations - Outerwear Pacts & Negotiations, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes: ILGWU negotiating committee at Dress Joint Council Meeting with Pres. Chaikin, Manuel Gonzalez - Manager Local 222, Frank Longo - Manager Local 89, Sam Newmaizer - Dress Joint Board Assistant Manager, Executive VP Wilbur Daniels, VP Murray Gross, Pres. Chaikin, VP David Gingold - Director Northeast Department, VP Edward Kramer - Director Eastern Region, Ray Shore - Assistant Northeaster Director, VP Frederick Siems, Sol Goldberg - Assistant Eastern Region Director, William Weiss - Assistant Manager Local 10, Sam Byer - Joint Council Secretary-Treasurer, and Mae Squillante - Joint Council Chairlady, 11/13/75; Council Chairlady Mae Squillante speaks at Joint Council Conclave with Exec. VP Wilbur Daniels, Pres. Chaikin, VP Murray Gross, 11/15/75; VP David Gingold, Director of Northeast Dept. speaks at Dress Joint Council Session with VP Frederick Siems, Sol Goldberg - Eastern Region Assistant General manager, William Weiss - Local 10 Assistant Manager, and VP Edward Kramer - Eastern Region General Manager, 11/15/75; Contract negotiations with VP Frederick R. Siems - chief union negotiator, Exec. VP Wilbur Daniels, General Counsel Max Zinny, VP Murray Gross - GM of Dress Joint Council, David Chrystal II dress union attorney, Sam Nemaizer - Joint Council Assistant General manager, Manager Frank Longo of Local 89, VP David Gingold - Northeast Director, Ray Shore - Northeast Assistant Director, Sam Byer - Council Secretary-Treasurer, Richard Sanfilippo, Eastern Region filed supervisor, Sol Goldberg region's assistant General Manager, and VP Edward Kramer - region's general manager, 12/1/75; Chairladies from the Williamsburg and Boro Park districts listen to Pres. Chaikin and VP Gross, 1/6/76; Pres. Chaikin in union and employer negotiations with employer attorneys Stanley Halpern and Charles Bollon and negotiators Richard Rubin of Popular Priced Dress manufacturers, Alex Redein of Affiliated Dress Manufactures, and Murray Cudrin of National Dress Manufactures, 2/15/76; Union negotiators confer in Room 2110, 2/15/76; Preparing for strike are Elisa Schmidt, Local 22 Manager Manuel Gonzalez, Business Agent Louise Delgado and Assistant Manager Sol Lipnack, 2/15/76; pres. Chaikin with TV Reporters, 2/15/76
- Agreements and Negotiations: Master Agreements (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Includes: Executive VP Wilbur Daniels presents formal demands for Jonathan Logan master agreement, with VP Nicholas Bonanno - Southeast Director, ILGWU Associate General Counsel Joseph Good, VP Sol Hoffman - Upper South Director, and VP Sam Janis - Ohio -Kentucky Director, 3/1/75; Representatives from Jonathan Logan plants study demands for new master agreements, Atlanta, 3/11/75; Members of union negotiating team (all women) listen to details of the Jonathan Logan master agreement, 4/1/75, Atlanta; Negotiations for contract renewal with Maidenform at the General Office, with Executive VP Wilbur Daniels, Director of the of master Agreements Department and VP Sol Hoffman - Director of the Upper South Department, Juanita Ballard, Business Agent Josephine Spence, Jessie Neely, Mary Messenger, West Virginia State Director Mario Marcello, Helen Hudkins, Doris McCoy, Odessa Fletcher, Business Agent Elizabeth Wiley, 4/14/75; Negotiations for agreement for Spartan Undies, a division if Jonathan Logan, with Henry Berger - Assistant Director of the Southeast Region, and South Carolina State Director Joe Ferguson heading the union's negotiating team, Spartanburg, South Carolina, 9/1/75; Union negotiators present demands for Bobbie Brooks Division master agreement in General Office council room, with Western Pennsylvania Manager Bernard Lurye, VP David Gingold - Northeast Department Director, Assistant Northeast Director Ray Shore, Eastern Missouri Manager Jerry Perlstein of the Central States Region, Associate General Counsel Joe Good, Executive VP Wilbur Daniels - Director of the Master Agreement Department and Chief Union negotiator, VP Sam Janis - Director of the Ohio-Kentucky Region, and Harry Berger - Assistant Director of the Southeast Region, 8/4/76; Union negotiators at General Office to conclude Bobbie Brooks master agreement, with Manager Jerry Perlstein - Eastern Missouri District Council, VP Sam Janis - Ohio-Kentucky Region Director, Exec. VP Wilbur Daniels - Director of the Mater Agreement Department, New York City, 10/1/76; Negotiations on master agreement for Barbizon Corporation, with Exec. VP Wilbur Daniels - Director of the Master Agreement Department, and VP Cornelius Wall - Director of the Western States Region, also some shop talks for Barbizon Agreement, with Executive VP Wilbur Daniels - Director of the Master Agreement Department, VP Cornelius Wall - Director of Western States Regions, and BA Carlo Leone, Provo, Utah, 5/15/77
- Agreements and Negotiations (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes: Meeting with Gene Boyer - President Country Miss, Sally Titerly, and John Jay - counsel for Country Miss, David Melman, Martin Vest, Wilbur Daniels, Lilian Kolwyck, 6/12/85; Justice articles on ESL and Import Bill, November 1985
- Agreements and Negotiations: master Agreements (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Includes: President Dubinsky speaks at Bobbie Brooks negotiating session, with (for the union) Edward Kramer, Sam Janis, Gus Tyler, Max Zimny, and Robert Rosenfeld, also some members of the shop workers' committee, 12/1/64; Jonathan Logan Conferees, Pres. David Dubinsky, George W. Taylor - impartial Chairman, Richard Schwartz - President of firm, Max Zimny - ILGWU Assistant General Counsel, VP Shelley Appleton - Local 23-25 manager, and William Isaacson - firm lawyer, 4/1/65; Maidenform pact signing in General Office, with Wilbur Daniels - Director of ILGWU Master Agreements Department, President Louis Stulberg, Dr. Joseph A. Coleman - firm president, Helen S. Szulimowski - Local 149 chairlady, Leon Milman - Local 149 manager, Peter Capitano - Local 160 manager, Ellis Rosenthal - firm Vice president, VP Angela Bambace - Upper South Dept. manager, Henry C. Happen - firm general counsel, David Benetar - firm counsel, Herman Lieberman, of firm, 8/31/66; Negotiations over terms of mast pact with Majestic Specialties, the union negotiators with employer representatives are Peter Nadash - manager of Western Pennsylvania District Council (sitting in for VP David Gingold Northeast Department Director), Wilbur Daniels - Director of Master Agreement Department, Sol Goldberg - Assistant General Manager of Eastern Region (representing VP Edward Kramer - regional head), San Janis - Ohio-Kentucky area director, New York, 7/1/67; Collective bargaining and women, 4/1/68; Arbitration session for cost-of-living wage increase for employees covered by Jonathan Logan master agreement, with David L. Cole - arbitrator, Nicholas Bonanno - South East Region Director, VP Wilbur Daniels - Director of the Master Agreements Department, Richard Schwartz - President of Jonathan Logan, Saul Z. Cohen - the firm's attorney, other company representatives, and workers from the involved plants, 10/13/70; ILGWU President Louis Stulberg speaks at Bobbie Brooks negotiating committee conference at ILGWU General Office, 12/1/71; VP Wilbur Daniels, Director of ILGWU Master Agreement Department, discusses pact renewal demands with ILG members and shop representatives from Bobbie Brooks plants, with Vice Presidents David Gingold and Sol C. Chaikin - Director and Associate Director of Northeast Department, VP Sam Janis - Director of Ohio-Kentucky Region, Glenn Clay - Assistant Director of Central States Region, and Jerry Perlstein - manager of North Missouri-Minnesota - Iowa District, 12/1/71; Negotiations for the renewal of the Barbizon Corp. master pact with management representatives and Vice Presidents Edward Kramer, Eastern Region and Wilbur Daniels, Master Agreements Department, General office in New York 2/1/71; Jonathan Logan negotiations of Misty Harbor with Wilbur Daniels - Master Agreements Director, Sol Hoffman - associate Upper South Director Harry Frankel - Maryland Director and Charles Sturm, Baltimore, 4/1/72; Bargaining session at General Office with union negotiators from Maidenform, and ILGWU Pres. Louis Stulberg and VP Wilbur Daniels - Director of Master Agreements Department, 4/15/72; Barbizon negotiations with Chaikin, VP Wilbur Daniels - Master Agreements Department and VP Edward Kramer - Eastern Region, 2/1/68; Barbizon agreement signing with Chaikin and VP Wilbur Daniels - Director of Master Agreements Department, 1968; Negotiations between ILGWU and Bobbie Brooks, Inc. at General Office with Pres. David Dubinsky, David L. Cole, committee chairman, and Maurice Saltzman, president of Bobbie Brooks Inc., no date; Unanimous vote of ILG members (mostly women) employed by Bobbie Brooks Superior Ave. plant in Cleveland for new agreement with the company, 2/15/63; Announcement of ILGWU - Bobbie Brooks permanent labor-management committee plan with Maurice Saltzman - company president, arbiter David L. Cole, ILGWU President David Dubinsky, firm's attorney William Rosenfeld, ILGWU Assistant General Counsel Max Zimny, General Secretary-Treasurer Louis Stulberg, VP Shelley Appleton, and Manager Max Goldenberg, at General Office, January 15 (year unspecified); ILG members from various parts of the country who participated in the successful negotiations of the Bobbie Brooks pact including President David Dubinsky, Rose Faranacci (Cleveland) Helena Herter (Pennsylvania), General secretary Treasurer Louis Stulberg, Catheryn Koziol (Pennsylvania), VP Shelley Appleton, Al Gargiulo, Julia John, Ruth Keene, John Hamilton, Bessie Durden, Synesta Great house (Cleveland), Ruth Perkins, Mary Keith, Frances Cooper, Earple Reams (Ma), Sarah Farling, James Sunday (Pennsylvania), Mildred Lawson, Winona Bell, Frank Peters (Arkansas), no date
- Anniversaries: Dubinskys 25th Anniversary, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes: David Dubinsky 25th Anniversary as President, at Unity House and Garden, June 15th and 16th, 1957
- Anniversaries: Anniversary Exhibit (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Includes: Pres.-Elect Chaikin describes embroidery craft to New York Mayor Abraham Beame as worker embroiders and Executive VP Wilbur Daniels and First VP E. Howard Molisani look on, June 1-15, 1975, New York; Model during Fashion Institute of Technology fashion show 5/20/75, New York; High School of Fashion Industries student during fashion show, New York, 5/21/75; Performance by Mai-Jen Dance Studio, McGraw-Hill Plaza, New York, 6/4/75; Women from various countries tour anniversary exhibit of International Women's Year, New York, June 1-15, 1975; Mayor Beame presents Pres.-Elect Chaikin with proclamation declaring June 3 "Garment Workers; Day", New York, June 1-15, 1975; Two retirees visit anniversary exhibit, June 1-15, 1975; ILGWU Chorus performs at opening of anniversary exhibit, June 1-15. 1975, New York; "Swinging 10" band of Cutters' Local 10 perform at opening of anniversary exhibit, New York, June 1-15, 1975
- Archives (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes: Photos of American Federation of Labor grants Certificate of Affiliations to ILGWU, 6/23/00; Boxes and file cabinets of documents in ILGWU Archives Department, no date; Researcher at ILGWU Archives Department, New York, no date; Various documents on desk at ILGWU Archives Department, New York, no date; Photos of ILGWU document concerning strike of Sample Tailors Society, document from 7/8/10 1910; Photo of ILGWU document concerning strike of Cloak and Skirt Makers in New York City, document from 6/18/10; Photo of AFL notebook, no date; Photo of historical photo, no date; Photo of letter from US President Franklin Roosevelt to David Dubinsky, president of International Ladies' Garment Workers' of America concerning Sidney Hillman and the Standard Knitting Mills award, document date: 12/8/41; Photo of letter from US President Harry Turban to ILGWU president David Dubinsky concerning Truman's decision to relieve General MacArthur of his command, document date: 4/18/51; Photo or letter from ILGWU General-Secretary-Treasurer John A. Dacha concerning a cloak workers strike in New York, document date: 7/26/19 1919; Document of Yiddish (photo) in 1913; Photo of Yiddish notebook, 1913; Photo of Thank you note from US President Franklin Roosevelt to ILGWU president David Dubinsky concerning Dubinsky's support of the president, document date: 6/5/41
- Awards (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Includes: William B. Frawley, grand prize winner in ILGWU's Next Great Designer Awards, Jun. 1982; Presentation of a film, no date
- Buildings and Monuments (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Includes: Copy of the Declaration of Independence, reprinted 7/4/81 in The New York Times; Statue of Liberty 10/26/81; unidentified building, no date; Women on steps in front of US Capitol Building, no date; People in front of Lincoln Memorial, Washington, DC; Gathering of many people in front of US Capitol Building; Washington, DC; Capitol Dome, Washington, DC 5/14/48; Capitol Dome, Washington, DC, no date; Photo of Capitol Building (torn from a book); John F. Kennedy taking oath of office at the Capitol, Washington, DC, no date; American flag in unidentified city, no date; American Flag in unidentified city, no date
- Canada (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes: ILGWU march, no date; ILGWU march, no date; ILGWU march, no date; Speaker at ILGWU rally, no date; Helen Busha, the first retiree of Local 568 pressing with Manager Ferguson, "568" Pres. Marge Crowe, and Business Agent Marlene Hill
- Central States (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Includes: At Tex-Son Strike, Rudy Hawkins, husband of a striker, is assaulted by police, San Antonio, Texas, 4/1/59; Janie Lozano received multiple scalp lacerations at Tex-Son strike in San Antonio, Texas, 2/15/60; Janie Lozano received multiple scalp lacerations at Tex-Son strike in San Antonio, Texas, 2/15/60; Checking Charlie O., official mascot of the Kansas City Athletics for the union label are Kansas City Joint Board Business Agent Rinaldo Panetta, chairman of labor's sports committee, Ethel Holk, Sec'y-treasurer of the Union Label and Service Trades Council, and Don Beibel. "A's" public relations director, 8/15/66; Central States ILR members Gertrude Hartung, Elizabeth Kimmel, Valeria Alexander and Sophie Gonzalez sign petitions for minimum wage law, San Antonio, Texas, 4/1/61; 50th Anniversary of Cloakmakers' Local 78 with local president Dave Cohen, VP Frederick Siems, Joint Board Manager Dan Robbins and charter members Hyman Weiss, Abe Israel, Margaret Ziebold, Max Lubin, Joe Schwartz, Max Boroz, and Sam Lipshitz, St. Louis, 2/1/61; Women on strike, no date; Two women on strike (ILGWU), no date; Children of Tex- Son strikers assemble prior to manning picket line, 7/1/59; Mass picketing by children of Tex-Son strikers, no date; Sharon Eubanks, member, Local 486, Zeigler, Illinois, Marlene Reams - member, Local 486, Zeigler, Illinois, and in car, Geneva Curry - member Local 486, Zeigler, Illinois, with four children: Karen Eubanks, Debbie Eubanks, Debbie Curry, and Melody Sue Reams, all supporting the Union label (won $25.00 for Union Label Car, 10/15/62; Three women of ILGWU on strike (VIC-GENE), no date; President Dubinsky speaks at mass membership meeting with Eleanora Kotoski - VP of St. Louis Board, Frank Rother - assistant regional director, Glen Clay - administrative assistant, Sam Mazzola - president of St. Louis Joint Board, Dan Robbins - manager of St. Louis Joint Board, VP Frederick Siems - Central States Regional Director, and Assistant President Gus Tyler, St. Louis, MO, no date; ILG members congratulate Congressman Richard Bolling of Missouri on winning primary election, 8/15/64; Woman on strike with son, no date; Holding a Missouri state flag (sent by Missouri Local 323) are Pfc. Ozburno, S/Sgt. Hack, and S/Sgt. Richard Schowengerdt in a Vietnam war zone, 6/1/67; Members of Central States Region Local 231, Essie Mae Weatherford, Minnie Cheek, Frankie Uhe - Vice President, Juanita Kiss, chairlady, Wilma Pruitt - President, Margaret Eisfelder, and Geraldine Pinski - financial secretary, sent food to servicemen in Vietnam, Pickneyville, Illinois, 10/5/66; Mary Perez and Onetta Johnson, members of Central States Local 453 picket Mode O'Day, in Ottawa, Kansas, 10/1/67, (joined by Lenn Collins - a child of the neighborhood); Nelly Don victor (group of people celebrating), 1968; Elvira Caldwell, Allene Peckman, Dean Gulbertson, James Prine, Mary Prine, Audrey Harrison, Dalma Taylor, Janice Welch, Jerry Welch; a shop organizing committee helped ILGWU election victory in Nelly Don plants, Nevada, 8/1/68; ILGWU truck in front of St. Louis skyline, 5/1/70; Vice President Glenn Clay and Gloria Moris, president of Arlington Hotel Workers' Organizing Committee, at "Solidarity Banquet" in Hot Springs, Arkansas, Nov. 1981; Dorothy Hoegele of the National Women's Conference Committee pins ERA button on ILGWU education committee member Elizabeth Bradley at the St. Louis Labor Council's training sessions, also BA Ruth Smith, Minnie Hayes, Gloria Lumpkin, Bradley and Ola Mayberry, Jan. 1982; Vice President Glenwood Clay presents a contribution from ILGWU to Missouri Democratic Senatorial candidate Harriett Woods, also Education Director Beth O'Brien and Ruth Smith, August, 1982; Central States ILG members in Missouri visit four members of the state's congressional delegation (four photographs): 1. with Rep. Harold Volkmer are Sadie Hustedde, Drucilla Anderson, Betty Dowell, Nettie Lambert, Delma Hendricks, Juanita Goodhart, 2. Kansas City activist Dorothy Devaney and Business Agent Cliftia Reissig with Rep. E. Thomas Coleman's aides Donna Due Coole and Ruth Coffman, 3 with Rep. Richard Gephardt are manager Winnie Lippman, Betty Montgomery, Jim Dozier and VP Glenn Clay regional director 4. visiting Rep. William Clay are Mary Tyler, Gloria Lumpkins, Mildred Lane and Louis Flowers, March 1982
- Chaikin (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Includes: Chaikin and Jimmy Carter, 7/22/76; Chaikin and Lazar Tepper at a meeting, June 1975; Chaikin and part of the ILGWU delegation at the AFL-CIO convention in New York, Dec. 1981; President Sol. C. Chaikin discusses New York City's transit problems with members of Local 155's executive board on November 9, also, VP Sol Greene local manager, Manager-elect Norman Lewis, and Local Pres. Murray Hendler, Dec. 1981; Pres. Sol C. Chaikin awarded a medal denoting the rank of knight in the Order of Merit of the Italian Republic by Consul General Giulio C. Di Lorenzo of the Italian Consulate in New York City, also Santo Pernicone of the Italian-American Labor Council, Vice consul Rosella Sranchini, Vice President Frank Longo - Local 89-48 manager, and VP Samuel Nemaizer - general manager of the New York Cloak-Dress Joint Board, 8/27/82; Chaikin with Mr. and Mrs. Aggett, Nov. 1982; Contact sheet and negatives of Chaikin and two unidentified men no date; Chaikin with Sen. R. Byrd, no date.
- Chaikin (Box 1, Folder 16)